<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-03-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Version i-lost-count</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/03/09/version-i-lost-count.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/03/09/version-i-lost-count.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-09T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-10T10:24:57+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Still not quite there, so I don't want to waste loads of PLA and print the thing just yet. I am getting very close though, unfortunately this is turning out to be a bit of a nightmare task!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="first" src="http://i.imgur.com/MT41xct.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="second" src="http://i.imgur.com/NYJYnTy.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole system is much flatter now and the stability improvements are HUGE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also learnt a neat trick from Andrew Leek at the lab. When printing my gears I was struggling to remove the 'brim' support material, and he suggested that I printed a bit slower and without the fans. It worked a treat. The prints are coming out great and they have a super smooth base which is perfect for reducing friction.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Inventor</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/03/08/inventor.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/03/08/inventor.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-08T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-10T10:20:33+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After much faffing around I finally decided to model and simulate the robot with Inventor 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="first" src="http://i.imgur.com/nijelVW.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="second" src="http://i.imgur.com/nJbP2mV.png" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="third" src="http://i.imgur.com/0eOzGTB.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I've used the software but with a little help I was able to grasp the basics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggled with exporting the models for the laser cutter for a while, eventually I found that you can select a face and then 'export face as' and save it to a dxf. Once you do that you will probably need to open the dxf and save it as an older version (2000) if you wish to import it into Rhino/Illustrator/Inkscape etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Dp5whsF6ZQs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>3D Printing</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/03/02/3d-printing.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/03/02/3d-printing.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-02T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-03T02:28:40+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So today I started to replace plywood components with PLA. It made a big improvement to the sturdiness of the model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="first" src="http://i.imgur.com/ePpT8NF.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first of many iterations during the printing process. It quickly became apparent that this blue was far too high above the gears and was causing the legs to twist when they walked. I managed to remedy this but wish I'd spent more time simulating the movement in 3D software rather than guessing it from some 2D flash animations I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="robot" src="http://i.imgur.com/6UDYlrm.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before RobotChallenge I will redesign the gear system, using Inventor, as the motors are having a lot of trouble powering the movement of the legs. Now that I have access to a printer I can make much finer teeth on the spur gears, and even have them at angles as shown below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="gears" src="http://i.imgur.com/uYNg3gs.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on making the central gear much smaller than it is now, and the two gears connected to the legs much larger. This will increase the torque of the system and mean that the legs move at a slower, more controlled pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also plan on changing the gait (walk-cycle) of the robot. Right now it looks a bit frantic! If only I had simulation software like Disney Research's…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/DfznnKUwywQ?list=UUM42XWqRoruK6bNkgbgoJMw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Strandbeest</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/03/01/strandbeest.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/03/01/strandbeest.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-01T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-03T01:36:35+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This was one of the clips that was at the back of my mind when I entered this competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/adm72GaaCJ8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A tale of Two Boards</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/02/28/a-tale-of-two-boards.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/02/28/a-tale-of-two-boards.html</id>
    <published>2014-02-28T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-03T02:02:01+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you probably know, the Arduino Robot is infact two Arduinos (Leonardos) on seperate boards, that communicate as a master/slave over I2C(?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The top board, the Control Board, behaves like a typical Arduino and it can send commands to the lower, Motor Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="top board" src="http://arduino.cc/en/uploads/Main/LottieLemon_figure_ref_top.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Motor Board simply responds to commands, it can however run without being connected to the upper board. The issue is that with default firmware it has very limited functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="bottom board" src="http://arduino.cc/en/uploads/Main/LottieLemon_figure_ref_bottom.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My electronics plans for this project are relatively straightforward. I want to send movement commands to the robot and receive feedback from sensors, such as strain on the motors and possibly things like temperature of the ground. For now I am happy testing the robot using just the lower board, but soon I will probably have to reflash it in order to use the IO pins without the upper board connected.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Algodoo</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/2014/02/24/algodoo.html"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/2014/02/24/algodoo.html</id>
    <published>2014-02-24T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-02-26T17:29:10+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After trying to get my head around lots of different software, I settled on using Algodoo (previously named Phun) for testing what my robot's walking motion might behave like. The nice thing about it, aside from seeing the actual motion path of the legs, will be that I can look at some of the forces involved and adjust the parts accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main problem this month has been that my Mac is its last legs. Switching it off is always a gamble as I don't know if I'll ever hear that familiar boot chime again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I'm sharing this because initially I wanted to use Autodesk Inventor, a Windows application. If you are a student I highly recommend you to register for their student scheme where you can get every Autodesk product for free. After beating my HDD into submission and finally getting Boot Camp running I quickly ran out of disk space so eventually gave up and resorted to using kiddy physics simulators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video below shows my first attempt at creating spur gears (cogs) haha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/7S8HxJ-PneI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next step will be to try and export what I design in more powerful software in a format that Algodoo understands. Whilst there are a couple of projects out there - svg2phun and an inscape plugin called phn_output - they seem quite dated and only have Japanese documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
